These are my kilns.
This kiln is a really huge one and because my work is so little I don't fire it.
This one fires on two twenty but this is a small electric kiln that actually fires on household current.
The way that a kiln works is that it pours and fires to a temperature of o cone six which is around twenty six hundred degrees.
So I use one of these little bars which are called a cone and when it gets to the proper temperature this little bar inside will melt.
I put it in, I put the cone in like this into the cone, cone holder and this little switch goes back and forth.
And when this melts it'll then trigger this latch to go, to go down and turn the kiln off automatically.
I put my porcelain in and I turn it on low for about an hour with, this is called a peep hole.
And the peep hole needs to be unplugged when you first start up on your kiln.
And I fire it for about an hour on low.
And I turn it up to medium and fire it for another hour.
All this time this lid is shut down.
And then I turn it on high for an hour.
And after an hour I plug up the peep hole and it will just go for anywhere from three to six hours longer depending on how much green ware is in your kiln.
Or how old your elements are.
Because as the elements get older, it takes longer to fire.
I have a head that I fired inside the kiln.
It?s sitting on a bed of what's called prop pet.
This is kind of like asbestos like material.
The shoulder plate I have the prop pet stuffed inside because if I just had it in the kiln like this when it gets hot it would tend to want to close down and break at the shoulders.
So I put this cottony prop pet stuff inside to support it during the firing.
When it goes in its white in color and very chalky and very fragile.
And then this it comes out of the kiln with this color.
As I mentioned earlier, the porcelain slip has the color in it.